Agustin Castro

Buenos Aires, Argentina agustin.castro2011@gmail.com +54 11 4035-0841

https://github.com/AgusCastro
https://www.linkedin.com/in/agustin-n-castro/

SUMMARY

Senior Full Stack Developer and Informatics Engineer graduate (2020) with 6 years of experience working as a developer and more than a year leading a successful development team.

I define myself as a full-stack developer with strong knowledge on the backend side and strong analytical and problem-solving abilities. Adept at resolving critical bugs and delivering exceptional solutions throughout the software development lifecycle focused on the client's solution required.

EXPERIENCE

NaN-LabsJava 11 - 17 | JavaScript | MySQL | MongoDB | Neo4j | SpringBoot |August 2021 - currentSenior Software EngineerReact.js AWS | Docker | Kubernetes | GitLab CI/CD | REST API | GraphQLRemote, Argentina

- Successful adaptation of the web app used by the sales department to Software as a Service(SaaS).
- Improved performance of the CI/CD with the reusability of docker images along the pipeline process. Decreased production deployment time from 40 minutes to 10.
- Increased the code coverage with unit and integration tests from 40% to 75%.
- Resolved a critical bug by applying constraints through triggers in the database's community version, reducing login errors by 95% and improving the overall user experience.
- Learned about leadership and communication skills, leading a team of 4 developers to deliver major features within strict timelines.
- Managed a dockerized application and deployed it using Kubernetes and Helm charts through GitLab CI/CD on Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE), optimizing deployment processes.
- Worked with AWS, using technologies such as AWS Lambda, EC2, and S3 to support the project requirements.

Quadion Technologies
SSr Full Stack Developer
Java 8 | Typescript | MySQL | SpringBoot | Angular
Google Cloud Platform | Docker | GitLab CI/CD | REST API

November 2020 - August 2021

Remote, Argentina

- Managed communication and reported work progress to a US-based client in monthly meetings, ensuring alignment with project goals and client satisfaction.
- Learned about a progressive migration process from Angular.js to Angular 10.
- Processed large files (up to 1GB) using Spring Batch and Cloud Storage.
- Management of MySQL database located on the Google Cloud Platform.

Besysoft S.A.

Java 8 | Typescript | MySQL | PostgreSQL

SpringBoot | Angular | REST API

June 2018 - November 2020

Buenos Aires, Argentina

- Developed and deployed 3 web applications using Angular (Front-end) and Java SpringBoot (Back-end).
- Managed and maintained four relational databases, including Oracle, MySQL, and PostgreSQL, ensuring data integrity.
- Systems development and support for a local bank.
- Development and support around, the Oracle Business Process Management Aqua Logic BPM 5.7

EDUCATION

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner Informatics Engineer January 2024 2016 - 2020

Universidad del Salvador (USAL)

Pilar, Buenos Aires

LANGUAGES

English | Advanced (B2) Spanish | Native

SKILLS

Programming Languages Java 8 - 11 - 17- 21 | JavaScript | Typescript

Databases MySQL | PostgreSQL | MongoDB | Neo4j

Frameworks Spring boot | NodeJS | Express | React.js | Angular.js | Angular 10

Technologies AWS | Google Cloud Platform | Docker | Kubernetes | GitLab CI/CD | REST API | GraphQL